<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on </title>
    <link>https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:25:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools for Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/tools-for-digital-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:25:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/tools-for-digital-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Tools for Digital Humanities Digital Humanities uses systematic utilization of digital resources for studying different disciplines of humanities along with the analysis of their application. It is characterized as a new way of studying that include transdisciplinary, and computational research and publication.
In Digital Humanities, by creating and utilizing new applications and techniques, it is possible to make new kinds of research and develop teaching techniques while still critiquing how these practices will affect the cultural heritage and digital culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/what-is-digital-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 22:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahida-perveen.github.io/SP-Blogs/what-is-digital-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Digital Humanities as per my understanding&amp;hellip; In the early 2000s with explosive development in Communications Technologies and the digital Revolution emerged a new discipline Digital Humanities. In DH, digital Technologies intersect with Humanities in the most interesting ways. This approach has new relevance in the context of the covid-19 that has probably dealt a knockout blow to the traditional approaches in education. Today, students have to break free from the tyranny of the printed text and move confidently into the fluid dynamics of interdisciplinarity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
